Welcome to our Understand Shipping Templates training.
In this video, you'll learn about what shipping templates are, how to configure your shipping templates,
how to set different shipping rate models, and how to offer free shipping.
By the end of the video, you'll know how to fill out a shipping template and set more accurate customer
delivery promises using Shipping Settings Automation.
Shipping templates enables you to customize options and then assign multiple ASINs to each template.
Within a shipping template, you can configure transit times and fees for both domestic and international
deliveries.
You can create up to 20 shipping templates to have different shipping options for groups of SKUs.
Domestically, you can assign specific fees within a region of a country.
Additionally, you can configure an option for customers to get expedited shipping and set a specific
price for this accelerated transit time.
From Seller Central, click the gear icon to open the Settings menu and then Shipping Settings.
On the Shipping Settings page, you'll see two tabs, General Shipping Settings and Shipping Templates.
By clicking the Shipping Templates tab, you can review existing templates, create new shipping templates,
assign SKUs to templates, or edit any existing templates.
To edit an existing template, click Edit Template.
From here, you can choose a rate model and your shipping options, such as free economy, standard
shipping, and expedited shipping.
You can also take a tour of your Shipping Settings page by clicking Take the Tour.
Make sure to check out our help pages on how to create new or edit existing shipping templates.
Additional help pages can help you with weekend carrier operations and holiday settings.
When setting shipping fees on your shipping template, you have two rate models to choose from, per
item weight-based and price-banded.
If you select per item weight-based, you can select a shipping fee for each item shipped, plus a
shipping fee for each additional item or pound that the first item weighs.
It's important to note that if you set your fee to $0, your customers will see a banner that says
Free Shipping, which typically leads to more product views and sales.
If you select price-banded, you can select a shipping fee for ASINs up to a specific limit and then
assign a different shipping fee for anything above that limit.
Additionally, if you're shipping in the US, you'll see a section called Free Economy.
This section offers customers the option to select a slower delivery promise that has free shipping.
But if you want to make free shipping your main customer delivery promise, set your standard shipping
fee to $0.
On your shipping templates, you can configure the transit time for your customer delivery promise.
You can manually estimate the transit time to each region and use the drop-down menu to assign the
number of days your products will take to arrive.
If you also want to learn more about the customer delivery promise, check out our video on shipping
settings.
Keep in mind that setting a longer transit time may cause your offer to look less appealing to customers.
We often find that sellers overestimate how long shipping takes.
You can also enable shipping settings automation, or SSA, to provide an automated calculation based
on your warehouse location, the location of the customer, and the carriers and ships that method
you use.
If you want to learn more about SSA, check out our shipping settings automation video.
In addition to your standard delivery promise, you can offer customers a faster delivery alternative
by enabling expedited shipping on your shipping template.
By doing so, you can configure a specific shipping fee to expedite the delivery, as well as which
regions you offer this service in.
Additionally, if you meet the requirements to offer premium shipping, you can enable one or two-
day delivery.
It's important to note that these customer delivery promises include same-day handling time for
orders received before 2 p.
m.
local time, plus the transit time.
For this reason, you must ensure your business can meet this turnaround time before enabling premium
shipping and selecting the regions where you want to offer these options.
After watching this video, you should now know what shipping templates are, how to navigate shipping
templates, how to set your shipping fees per item or by price band, and how to offer free shipping.
Make sure to return to the shipping settings page to review and update your shipping settings or
templates as needed.
This concludes our training on shipping templates.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.